Guide to the UTU Records
UTU Records
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
UTU Records, 1883-1993
5139
United Transportation Union (UTU)
118.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Collective bargaining documents of the United Transportation Union, agreements & correspondence.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The United Transportation Union (UTU) is headquartered in Cleveland, Ohio. It is a broad-based, transportation labor union representing about 125,000 active and retired railroad, bus, mass transit, and airline workers in the United States. In 1968 four brotherhoods' became interested in joining together to make one transporatation union, the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, the Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen and the Switchmen's Union of North America. The new union was to be called the United Transportation Union and came into existence on January 1, 1969, after an overwhelming vote of the 4 unions on December 10, 1968, in Chicago. The first president was Charles Luna, formerly president of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, and had 230,000 members. The International Association of Railway Employees joined in 1970. The Railroad Yardmasters of America joined the union in 1985.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collective bargaining documents of the United Transportation Union, agreements & correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
United Transportation Union
Subjects:
Mediation and conciliation, Industrial -- United States; Collective labor agreements -- Railroads -- United States; Transport workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Wages -- Transport workers -- United States
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
5139 AV: UTU Audio-Visual Material
5139 MB: UTU Memorabilia
5139 P: UTU Photographs
6055: UTU Additional Collective Bargaining Agreements
6023: UTU Additional Records
5164: UTU Canada Records
5622: UTU New York State Legislative Board Selected Files
5711: UTU New York State Legislative Director Files
5589: UTU Vice-President's Office George W. Legg Subject Files
5501 AV: UTU. Young Leadership Conference Audio recordings
5196: UTU Ladies' Auxiliary Iowa Joint Board Minutes
CONTAINER LIST
- Severance Pay-- SUNA Employees, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Group Research, Inc. Directory, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Handbook on anti-Communist, Conservative, and Republican organizations and individuals at the height of the Cold War. Property of SUNA.
- Unification Documents, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Invoices (SUNA), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Invoices (BRT), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Invoices (ORC & B), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Invoices (BLF & E), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Lou Chester, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Copies of Bills, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Office, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Articles and Amendments to Constitution (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Articles and Amendments to Constitution (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Articles and Amendments to Constitution (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Articles and Amendments to Constitution (4 of 4), 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Final folder in a four-part series. Previous three folders are in Box 1 of this series.
- Pennsylvania Railroad and New York Central Railroad Merger (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Analysis of merger between PA RR and NY Central RR
- Lists, Committee Reports, Officers, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- UTU Marker Dedication, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- UTU Press Packets (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Report to General Policy Committee, Books 1 and 2, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Two separate books consolidated into one folder.
- Unification Agreement (Box 2, Folder 7)
  One of a series of Unification Agreement drafts.
- Unification Agreement, Constitution (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Proposed Unification Agreement, Constitution v.1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Attempts at Merger (BLE & UTU), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Transfers: "S" to "T" Locals and L-M Reports (SUNA), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Proposed Unification & Agreement v.2 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- BRT Convention, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Hollywood, FL.
- Consolidation of Locals and Transfer of Members, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Consolidation of C-26 and T-397, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Unification Agreement and Constitution, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- UTU Newspaper Announcement, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Officers Assigned (Territories), 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- UTU Merger, SUNA Resolution to that Effect, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- UTU Insurance (1 of 2), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Part 1 of a series
- UTU Insurance (2 of 2), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- The Unity Move in Railroad Labor, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Two pamphlet booklets on the history of the merger. Year listed is approximate.
- BLE Independence (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Abandonments (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Administration of Agreements: Pay Claims-- Road/Yard (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Administration of Agreements: Other Procedural Issues, General (Box 4, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Alcoholism- Communications: Congressional/Federal Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Alcoholism- Communications: NCOA Minutes, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Alcoholism- Communications: NCOA Minutes, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Alcoholism- Communications: Outreach and Programming, 1977-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Alcoholism- Communications: Media and Public Relations, 1975-1985 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Alcoholism- Communications: UTU Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Alcoholism- Conferences: Boston, MA, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Alcoholism- Conferences: College Station, TX, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Alcoholism- Conferences: Ithaca, NY, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Cornell University
- Alcoholism- Conferences: Los Angeles, CA, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Alcoholism- Conferences: Louisville, KY, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Alcoholism- Conferences: Milwaukee, WI, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Alcoholism- Conferences: New Orleans, LA, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  University of New Orleans
- Alcoholism- Conferences: Topeka, KS, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Alcoholism- Conferences: Washington, DC, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Alcoholism: EAP Implementation (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Alcoholism- Reports and Studies: Delay Report, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Alcoholism- Reports and Studies: FRA Report, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Alcoholism- Reports and Studies: FRA Survey, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Alcoholism- Reports and Studies: New England and Drug Use Surveys, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Alcoholism- Reports and Studies: Prevalence Panel Report, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  Cover page only. Rest of report missing.
- Alcoholism- Reports and Studies: Project REAP Statistics, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Alcoholism: Railroad Union Codes and Names (Box 4, Folder 27)
- American Soybean Association (Box 4, Folder 28)
- AMTRAK: 3C/Ohio (Box 4, Folder 29)
- AMTRAK: Background (Box 4, Folder 30)
- AMTRAK: Congressional Memoranda, Records, Statements, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- AMTRAK: Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Letters sent to/from other railroad companies.
- AMTRAK: Department of Transportation (Box 4, Folder 33)
- AMTRAK: Employment Application (Box 4, Folder 34)
- AMTRAK: Employment Passes (Box 4, Folder 35)
- AMTRAK: Employee Protection (Box 4, Folder 36)
- AMTRAK: Joint Labor/Management Productivity Council (Box 4, Folder 37)
- AMTRAK: Labor and Management (Box 4, Folder 38)
- AMTRAK: Media Publications- General (Box 4, Folder 39)
  Publications regarding AMTRAK from companies including but not limited to: The New York Times, U.S. News and World Report, and the Wall Street Journal.
- AMTRAK: Media Publications- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 40)
  Publications regarding AMTRAK from railroad-affiliated groups, including but not limited to: Passenger Train Journal, BMWE, and Railway Age.
- AMTRAK: Northeast Corridor (Box 4, Folder 41)
- AMTRAK: Op-Eds (Box 4, Folder 42)
- AMTRAK: Press Releases (Box 4, Folder 43)
- AMTRAK: Promotional Material (Box 4, Folder 44)
- AMTRAK: Railpax (Railroad Passenger Service Act), 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  Information pertaining to bill that made AMTRAK possible.
- AMTRAK: Union Representation Disputes (Box 4, Folder 46)
  Smear campaigns against UTU, Amtrak Service Workers Council, BRAC, and TWU.
- Baltimore (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Benefits (Box 4, Folder 48)
- BLE- Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers (Box 4, Folder 49)
- BRAC-86 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Buffalo-1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Bullet Train, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Burlington Northern (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Caboose (Box 5, Folder 4)
- California State Railroad Museum (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Carey Transportation Company (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Carey Transportation Co. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Jimmy Carter (Box 5, Folder 8)
- UTU Chairmen (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Chicago Labor-Management (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Chicago Commuter Crash, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Chicago Mo-Pac System, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Collective Bargaining (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Committee After True Cooperative Harmony (CATCH), 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Compulsory Arbitration (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Conrail, Pt. 1 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Conrail, Pt. 2 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Conrail, Pt. 3 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Conrail Piggyback Proposals, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Conrail 1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- FRA Review, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Conrail (82), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Conrail 7/1/82 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Conrail, Pt. 1 (Box 5.1, Folder 1)
- Conrail, Pt. 2 (Box 5.1, Folder 2)
- Conrail, Pt. 3 (Box 5.1, Folder 3)
- Conrail 83, 1983 (Box 5.1, Folder 4)
- Conrail Abandonments (Box 5.1, Folder 5)
- BRUTE (Better Results Utilizing Team Efficiency), 1989 (Box 5.1, Folder 6)
  From Buffalo, NY.
- CRU/RLEA (Box 5.1, Folder 7)
- Conrail: Internal Communication (Box 5.1, Folder 8)
- Conrail, Labor-Management Cooperative Program (Box 5.1, Folder 9)
- Conrail: Labor/Management Project (Box 5.1, Folder 10)
- Conrail: Labor-Management Task Force (Box 5.1, Folder 11)
- Congressman Lundine H-M TF Effort HR 2596-2597 (Box 5.1, Folder 12)
- Conrail: Media and PR (Box 5.1, Folder 13)
- Conrail: Memoranda (Box 5.1, Folder 14)
- Conrail: Publications (Box 5.1, Folder 15)
- Conrail: Reports and Reviews (Box 5.1, Folder 16)
- Conrail: US Congress (1985) (Box 5.1, Folder 17)
- Consolidated Rail + Other (Box 5.1, Folder 18)
- Consist of Crew: Carrier Level (Box 5.1, Folder 19)
- Constitutional Amendments (Box 5.1, Folder 20)
- Convention (Box 5.1, Folder 21)
- Cornell (Box 5.1, Folder 22)
- Cost of US Wars (Box 5.1, Folder 23)
- Cottrell, 1972 (Box 5.1, Folder 24)
- DH Proposal for PC, 1973 (Box 5.1, Folder 25)
- De Paul Labor-Management Conference, 1974 (Box 5.1, Folder 26)
- Deregulation, 1980 (Box 5.1, Folder 27)
- Discipline Case- Derailment, Ohio, 1973 (Box 5.1, Folder 28)
- Dispute Over Representation Rights: UTU (BLFE) v. BLE, 1969 (Box 5.1, Folder 29)
- Drug Testing (Box 5.1, Folder 30)
- Dues and Fees- Objector Policy, Etc. (Box 5.1, Folder 31)
- Emergency Board on FEC (Box 5.2, Folder 1)
- Emergency Bds. 194-195 (Box 5.2, Folder 2)
- Employee Assistance Program (Box 5.2, Folder 3)
- Engineering Foundation Conference, 1973 (Box 5.2, Folder 4)
- Engineering Foundation Conference on Goods Transportation in Urban Areas, 1973 (Box 5.2, Folder 5)
- Feather bedding (Box 5.2, Folder 6)
- Federal Railway Admin- Tampering with Safety Devices (Box 5.2, Folder 7)
- Finances- National (Box 5.2, Folder 8)
- Firemen Issue UTU (E) v. BLE (Box 5.2, Folder 9)
- Firemen Manning Issue (Box 5.2, Folder 10)
- General Chairmen, Pt. 1 (Box 5.2, Folder 11)
- General Chairmen, Pt. 2 (Box 5.2, Folder 12)
- Great Plains Rail Shippers (Box 5.2, Folder 13)
- Houston (Box 5.2, Folder 14)
- Houston- New Orleans, 1983 (Box 5.2, Folder 15)
- Hours of Service - National Legislation (Box 5.2, Folder 16)
- Human Relations at Work Books (Supervisor's Tests) (Box 5.2, Folder 17)
- Illinois Central Gulf (Box 5.2, Folder 18)
- IH + B (Box 5.2, Folder 19)
- Industrial College Armed Forces- Nov. 29, 1973 Meeting (Box 5.2, Folder 20)
- Industrial College Armed Forces Meeting- Nov. 5, 1974 (Box 5.2, Folder 21)
- Industrial College Armed Forces Meeting- 12/9/74, 1974 (Box 5.2, Folder 22)
- Industrial College of the Armed Forces: Week of December 7, 1975 (Box 5.2, Folder 23)
- Industrial College of the Armed Forces 7/76, 1976 (Box 5.2, Folder 24)
- Industrial College of the Armed Forces 3/14/77, 1977 (Box 5.2, Folder 25)
- Insurance (Box 5.2, Folder 26)
- Interdivisional Runs (Up to 1968)- National Level (Box 5.2, Folder 27)
- Jersey Central (Box 5.2, Folder 28)
- Kyle RR Co. (Box 5.2, Folder 29)
- Labor Studies Program (Box 5.2, Folder 30)
- Ladies Aux. (Box 5.2, Folder 31)
- Leave of Absence from NY Central (Box 5.2, Folder 32)
- LDL-1242-BFIO (Box 5.2, Folder 33)
- Lehigh Valley (Nash) on NE Consolidation (Box 5.2, Folder 34)
- Liberal Arts Colleges- NY State (Box 5.3, Folder 1)
- Long Island Rail Road (LIRR) (Box 5.3, Folder 2)
- George Meary Center (Box 5.3, Folder 3)
  Prep work for a labor history exhibition at the Smithsonian Institution
- McGovern + Anti-Labor Bias in School Books (Box 5.3, Folder 4)
- Meyers Minutes (Box 5.3, Folder 5)
- Milwaukee (Box 5.3, Folder 6)
- Milwaukee Road (Box 5.3, Folder 7)
- Labor-Management Seminar, 1976 (Box 5.3, Folder 8)
- Misc. (Box 5.3, Folder 9)
- Mondale/Ferraro, 1976 (Box 5.3, Folder 10)
- National Safety Council - Oct. 30 + 31, Nov. 1 (Box 5.3, Folder 11)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 5.3, Folder 12)
- Northeast Rail Crisis (Box 5.3, Folder 13)
- Operation Red Block: Advertising/Publicity (Box 5.3, Folder 14)
- Operation Red Block: Communication (Box 5.3, Folder 15)
- Operation Red Block: Enforcement, Procedures, Implementation (Box 5.3, Folder 16)
- Operation Red Block: Handbooks (Box 5.3, Folder 17)
- Operation Red Block: Publications (Box 5.3, Folder 18)
- Operation Red Block- Surveys and Reports: Atlanta, 1985 (Box 5.3, Folder 19)
- Operation Red Block- Surveys and Reports: Cleveland (Box 5.3, Folder 20)
- Operation Red Block- Surveys and Reports: Kansas City, 1985 (Box 5.3, Folder 21)
- Operation Red Block- Surveys and Reports: Las Vegas, 1985 (Box 5.3, Folder 22)
- Operation Red Block- New England Drug Use Survey, 1982 (Box 5.3, Folder 23)
- Operation Red Block- Surveys and Reports: New York, 1985 (Box 5.3, Folder 24)
- Operation Red Block- Surveys and Reports: Prevention (Box 5.3, Folder 25)
- Operation Red Block- Surveys and Reports: Workbook (Box 5.3, Folder 26)
- ORTA (Box 5.3, Folder 28)
- Penn Central (Box 5.3, Folder 29)
- Penn Central: Annual Financial Reports (Box 5.3, Folder 30)
- Penn Central: Importance (Box 5.3, Folder 31)
- Penn Central: Income Productivity (Box 5.3, Folder 32)
- Penn Central: Statistics, Employment (Box 5.3, Folder 33)
- Pension Plan, BRT (Box 5.4, Folder 1)
- Poverty (Box 5.4, Folder 2)
- Public Relations (Box 5.4, Folder 3)
- Quality Circles (Box 5.4, Folder 4)
- Quality of Work Life: Cleveland, OH 1983 (Box 5.4, Folder 5)
- Rail Bargaining (Box 5.4, Folder 6)
- Rail Safety (Box 5.4, Folder 7)
- Rail Safety- Kansas (Box 5.4, Folder 8)
- Railroad Labor Studies Program: NYS School of ILR. Buffalo, NY (Box 5.4, Folder 9)
- Project REAP: Background Material (Box 5.4, Folder 10)
  1 of 2 copies.
- Project Reap: Background Material (Box 5.4, Folder 11)
  2 of 2 copies.
- Project REAP Overview (Box 5.4, Folder 12)
- Railroad Personnel Association (Box 5.4, Folder 13)
- Railroad Unemployed + New Entrants (Box 5.4, Folder 14)
- RLEA (Box 5.4, Folder 15)
- Railway Transportation Union (Box 5.4, Folder 16)
- Rank + File Activity, 1972-1973 (Box 5.4, Folder 17)
- Rate Tables (Box 5.4, Folder 18)
- Ronald Regan, Part 1 (Box 5.4, Folder 19)
- Ronald Reagan, Part 2 (Box 5.4, Folder 20)
- Ronald Reagan, Part 3 (Box 5.4, Folder 21)
- Representation Election (Box 5.4, Folder 23)
- Requisition Forms (Box 5.4, Folder 24)
- Research: BR Calkins (Box 5.4, Folder 25)
- Railroad Retirements and Social Security (Box 5.4, Folder 26)
- Retirement (Box 5.4, Folder 27)
- Red Block (Box 5.3, Folder 27)
  See: Operation Red Block.
- Rule "G" (Box 5.5, Folder 1)
- Safe Crew Law (Box 5.5, Folder 2)
- Safety (Box 5.5, Folder 3)
- Safety Flagging (Box 5.5, Folder 4)
- Safety (Originally Railroad Safety) (Box 5.5, Folder 5)
- Scholarship Programs (Box 5.5, Folder 6)
- Seniority (Box 5.5, Folder 7)
- Shippers Advisory Brand (Box 5.5, Folder 8)
- Smithsonian Folk life Festival (Box 5.5, Folder 9)
- Soo Line Investigation (Box 5.5, Folder 10)
- SP Commissions (Box 5.5, Folder 11)
- SP Drug Case (Box 5.5, Folder 12)
- Southern Pacific Railroad Presentation Vote (Box 5.5, Folder 13)
- Southern Pacific Representation Vote (Box 5.5, Folder 14)
- Southern Pacific (Atlantic Line) Yard and Road; Southern Pacific (Pacific Yard) Locals and Road (Box 5.5, Folder 15)
- SPROC-72 (Box 5.5, Folder 16)
- Southern Ry-School McDonough (Box 5.5, Folder 17)
- Steelworks- USU No Strike-Pact (Box 5.5, Folder 18)
- David Stockman (Box 5.5, Folder 19)
- Taxes (Box 5.5, Folder 20)
- Train & Engine Service Employment, Pt. 1 (Box 5.5, Folder 21)
- Train & Engine Service Employment, Pt. 2 (Box 5.5, Folder 22)
- Trains Without Cabooses (Box 5.5, Folder 23)
- Training Conferences (Box 5.5, Folder 24)
- Truck Labor Studies- ILR NY City (Box 5.5, Folder 25)
- Trucks (Box 5.5, Folder 26)
- UROC (Box 5.5, Folder 27)
- University of Texas (Box 5.5, Folder 28)
- UTU Convention 1971 (Box 5.5, Folder 29)
- UTU Convention 1971- Opposition to Current Union Administration (Box 5.5, Folder 30)
- UTUIA Scholarships (Box 5.5, Folder 31)
- UTU Convention, 1983 (Box 5.5, Folder 32)
- UTU Electioneering Materials, Convention 1979 (Box 5.5, Folder 33)
- Wage Movement, Sec. 6- 1984 (Box 5.5, Folder 34)
- Wage Movement, 1985 (Box 5.5, Folder 35)
- Wage Rules Settlement- March '73 (Box 5.5, Folder 36)
- Waterway Roles in the Transport System (Box 5.5, Folder 37)
- What is a Railroad? (Box 5.5, Folder 38)
- Whatever Happened to the Labor Movement? (Box 5.5, Folder 39)
- Williamsport & Southern Corp. Preliminary System Plan- Lake Erie Corridorail 1/5/85, 1985 (Box 5.5, Folder 40)
- WISC (Box 5.5, Folder 41)
- Administration of Agreements- Firemen Issues (Box 6, Folder 1)
- McCabe- Cornell Grants (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Papers pertaining to Douglas McCabe, Ph.D. '77.
- Operation Redblock (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Rank and File Action- Dissidence (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Regarding the Election of Delegates to the National Convention- Dispute Over the Use of the Weighted Ballot (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Scholarships (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Seaboard Coast Line Railroad (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Southern Pacific (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Task Force (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Union Papers I (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Union Papers II (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Alcoholism (Box 7, Folder 1)
- BLE (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Bureau of International Labor Affairs (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Circular letters (BLF&E) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Re: City of Buffalo (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Conrail (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: 1969 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Correspondence: 1970 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: 1971 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Correspondence: 1972 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Correspondence: 1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Correspondence: 1975 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Correspondence: 1976 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Correspondence: 1977 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Correspondence: 1978 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Correspondence: 1979 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Correspondence: 1980 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Correspondence: 1981 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Correspondence: 1982 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Correspondence: 1983 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Correspondence: 1984 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Correspondence: 1985, Part 1 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Correspondence: 1985, Part 2 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Correspondence: 1986, Part 1 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Correspondence: 1986, Part 2 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Correspondence: 1987, Part 1 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Correspondence: 1987, Part 2 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Correspondence: 1987, Part 3 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Correspondence: 1988, Part 1 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Correspondence: 1988, Part 2 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Correspondence: 1989, Part 1 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Correspondence: 1989, Part 2 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Memoranda, FAQs, Letters (Box 7, Folder 33)
- D.O.T. (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Dues and Strike Funds (Box 7, Folder 35)
- General Committee of Adjustment (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Gov't Legislation (Box 7, Folder 37)
- AARE Educational Material (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Burlington-Northern (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Canadian National Railway Arbitration Case (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Central of Georgia GS-171 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Chesser, Al H.- President (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Documents pertaining to Al Chesser during his Presidency of UTU.
- Chicago & North Western GS-233 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Chicago, Rock Island & Pacific. GS-277 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Clinchfield Railroad GO-283 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- CMST P&P (W) GO-267 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Collins, Daniel (Part 1) (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Collins, D.W. (Part 2) (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Collins, D.W. (Part 2) (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Collins, D.W.- Thank You Letters (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Congressional Bills Code Books (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Conrail N+S C851 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- CGW GS-256 (Dissolved 1-1-70) (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Crew Consist (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Cuyahoga Valley Ry. (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Denver & Rio Grande Western GS-310 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- EAP Kansas City June 2, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- E-L Consolidation (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Erie Lackawanna (Box 8, Folder 22)
- C. Ferguson- Penn Central (W) (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Fort Worth & Denver GS-364 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Fred Hardin (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Free Enterprise (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Gov't Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Historical Newsletters: 1st+3rd Monday (Box 8, Folder 28)
  UTU Newsletters
- Re: Improved Utilization of Railway Cars (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Interstate Commerce Commission: Employment Table (1969-1980) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Job Benefit Fund- National Scale (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Labor- Liberal Arts College- Buffalo (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Labor and Mgmt. Council (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Labor Law, Part 1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Labor Law, Part 2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Labor Law, Part 3 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Los Angeles Junction (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Mediation Agreement and Ratification (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Membership (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Membership + Chairman's Lists (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Memo of Understanding. - Legislative Assets (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Milwaukee- 1969 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Misc. (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Monthly Reports (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Mothers Against Drunk Driving (Box 9, Folder 16)
- National Association Shipping Advisory Board Meeting 05/08/75 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- New Right to Work (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Non-Ops. Arbs. From Home (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Northern Pacific GS-738 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Notes from Ad-Hoc Transportation Meetings (Box 9, Folder 22)
- (NYC) Penn Central GO-619 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- NYC Rail Freight Meeting Minutes 1979 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Operation Red Block: Complaints and Incidents (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Operation Red Block: DOT/FRA Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Operation Red Block: General Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Operation Red Block: Labor Mgmt. Task Forces (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Operation Red Block: Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Operation Red Block: National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Operation Red Block: Newspaper Clippings (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Operation Red Block: Policies, FAQs (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Operation Red Block: Thank You Letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Penn-Central (W): "Check-Off" (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Penn Central's Impact on National Transportation Policy (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Pittsburgh- Univ. Penn. Hotel 6/20/83 (Box 10, Folder 9)